codewars.com 2018-12-21

# Codewars

This privacy notice tells you about the information we collect from you when you use our website. 

## Who are we?

Codewars is operated by Qualified, Inc. Our address is 1930 Village Center Cr #3-8713, Las Vegas, NV 89134. You can contact us by post at the above address, by email at [privacy@qualified.io](mailto:privacy@qualified.io). 

We are not required to have a data protection officer, so any enquiries about our use of your personal data should be addressed to the contact details above.

## How we use your information

Certain visitors to our websites choose to interact with Codewars in ways that require Codewars to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Codewars gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who sign up at [Codewars.com](http://codewars.com/) to provide an email address, and other potential information to necessary for processing payments. In each case, Codewars collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Codewars. Codewars also may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. Codewars does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. Visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

### When you use our website

Like most website operators, Codewars collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Our purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how our visitors use its website. From time to time, Codewars may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

When you use our website to browse our content and view the information we make available, a number of cookies are used by us and by third parties to allow the website to function, to collect useful information about visitors and to help to make your user experience better.

Some of the cookies we use are strictly necessary for our website to function. Codewars visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using our websites, with the drawback that certain features of our websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

A visitor's IP address may be logged within our system, typically for debugging purposes, separate from our system application databases. The IP address may remain stored within our logs for up to 3 months.

### When you purchase a subscription from our website

When you purchase a subscription from us, we may ask you for your name, address, contact telephone number, email address and credit card information.

We will use your information to verify your credit card details for your purchase, process your order and to subscribe you to our products. We will also send you a receipt via email and we may use your telephone number to contact you regarding your purchase.

We require this information in order to process your payment, deliver your products or services and fulfill our contract with you.

Your information is stored on our website and on our cloud servers, both of which are based within the United States. Your credit card details are passed directly to a third-party payment processor which is based in the United States and is certified to the EU-US Privacy Shield (which requires effective safeguards for your information). We do not retain your credit card information. 

We keep your order information for an indefinite period, for our accounting purposes.

### When you take or create kata via our website

The primary function of Codewars is to create and/or solve coding challenges, which we call kata. Each time you complete a kata, your solution with the username that you specify may be shown within a list of other solutions for that kata. Each time you publish a kata that you created, your kata will be displayed within our public kata directory, with your username and profile link associated to the content.

We keep your user information for as long as you have a user account with us.

You may decide to delete your account at any time. A deleted account will result in the username being removed from all content, including kata and solutions, associated with that name. In its place will be a generated non-personally identifiable name. The related profile page will be deleted.

At any point you may request that your personally identifiable information by removed. You can do so by deleting your account from your user settings page. To submit a request regarding your personal data by email or post, please use the contact information provided above in the "Who Are We" section of this policy.

### When you take part in our feedback survey

When you take part in our feedback survey, we record your name, your email address, and may ask for your organization name, your job role and your answers to questions we ask about your opinion of, and use of, our products and services.

We use this information to develop and improve our products and services and our customer relationships. Your job role, organization and some or all of your comments may be publicly displayed on our website as a testimonial. We will do this based on our legitimate interest in marketing our products and services.

Your details are shared with a third party surveys system which is based within the United States.

We do not use the information you provide to make any automated decisions that might affect you.

Your personal data is stored for three years, or for as long as we are marketing the product or services that the review refers to, whichever is shorter. You may ask us to remove a testimonial that is based on your feedback from our website at any time.

### Information Protection and Disclosure

Codewars discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on our behalf or to provide services available at our websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using our websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Codewars will not share with or sell your potentially personally-identifying information to other organizations for commercial purposes, except when we have your permission to provide you products or services that you’ve requested. If you are a registered user of a Codewars website and have supplied your email address, Codewars may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Codewars and our products. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Codewars takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information

## Your rights as a data subject

By law, you can ask us what information we hold about you, and you can ask us to correct it if it is inaccurate. If we have asked for your consent to process your personal data, you may withdraw that consent at any time.

If we are processing your personal data for reasons of consent or to fulfill a contract, you can ask us to give you a copy of the information in a machine-readable format so that you can transfer it to another provider.

If we are processing your personal data for reasons of consent or legitimate interest, you can request that your data be erased.

You have the right to ask us to stop using your information for a period of time if you believe we are not doing so lawfully. 

Finally, in some circumstances you can ask us not to reach decisions affecting you using automated processing or profiling.

To submit a request regarding your personal data by email or post, please use the contact information provided above in the Who Are We section of this policy.

## Updates to this policy

We regularly review and, if appropriate, update this privacy policy from time to time, and as our services and use of personal data evolves. If we want to make use of your personal data in a way that we haven’t previously identified, we will contact you to provide information about this and, if necessary, to ask for your consent. 

This policy was last updated on May 22nd 2018.
